It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
(Niten'ichiryu: 二天一流, Musashiryu; the art of using two swords)
천공환, 천지환과 이도류를 자기 것으로 만든 무사시는 이천일류의 완성을 노린다.
Everyone suffered from the huge centipede of Goemondo, a grand thief.
대도둑 고에몬도의 거대 지네에 고통받는 무사시 일행.
But during that fight, Musashi finally opened his eyes towards Niten'ichiryū.
그러나 그 전투 중에서 무사시는 결국 이천일류를 개안하였다.
(I am unsure with some proper nouns used in this episode, so they might be wrong)
누에가 우는 밤은 무섭소
Stop, Kojirō!
멈추시오, 코지로!
Hey, Kojirō, have a match with me!
자, 코지로, 승부를 보시오!
That's enough, Musashi! Senhime is astonished of you!
작작 좀 해라, 무사시! 센히메 님이 기막혀하고 있지 않냐!
Someone might be looking down on me, but I am dead serious-dasu!
기막혀할 사람은 기막혀하겠지만 난 진심이오!
I know that you're going to be dead if you're dead serious.
진검을 뽑아들었으니 진검승부의 마음가짐을 하고 있다는 건 잘 알겠어.
You shouldn't make bad jokes-dasu...
서투른 농담은 하지 마시오...
It was bad?!
서투르다고?!
Musashi gets angry so easily, so you shouldn't give attention to him.
무사시는 쉽게 발끈하니까 신경쓰지 않는 편이 좋습니다.
That's right! I get angry easily-dasu! Now, Kojirō, face me-dasu!
그렇소! 난 쉽게 발끈하오! 자, 코지로, 승부를 보시오!
I will defeat Tsubamegaeshi with Niten'ichiryū!
이천일류로 훌륭하게 츠바메가에시를 물려내 보이겠소!
Sure, I get that Niten'ichiryū is great. But Musashi, what is the purpose of this trip?
알았어, 알았어! 이천이류는 대단해. 그렇지만, 무사시, 이 여행의 목적은...
To protect Osenchan-dasu.
오센짱을 지키는 것이오.
Right. So just know that I'll going to face you as soon as the trip is over.
그래. 그러니까 여행이 끝나면 바로 상대해 줄 테니까.
The trip will never end-dasu.
여행은 안 끝나오...
-Huh? -Why?
-어? -왜?
Osenchan will never find a new husband-dasu!
오센짱은 영원히 새신랑 못 찾으니까이오!
I'm sorry-dasu!
미안하오!
Stop right there, Musashi!
멈춰라, 무사시!
Stop!
멈춰!
-If you act violent like that, you'll never get a husband-dasu! -Musashi!
-그렇게 난폭하면 죽어도 새신랑 못 찾소! -무사시!
Are we at Sendai village yet-dasu?
센다이 마을은 아직이오...
We're late only because you did all the stupid things possible, Musashi.
무사시가 멍청한 짓만 골라서 하니까 늦어졌잖냐.
I see Sendai village!
센다이 마을이야!
Huh?
어?
That must be Sendai village-dasu!
저것이 센다이 성이오!
Food, food, food!
밥밥밥~
Hey, Musashi!
어이, 무사시!
Damn...
정말...
Food is calling me-dasu!
밥이 날 부르고 있소...
Osenchan, on your back-dasu!
오센짱, 뒤이오!
Who is it-dasu?! It is cowardly to pounce out of nowhere-dasu!
대체 누구시오! 갑자기 덤벼들다니 비겁하오!
Musashi!
무사시!
Aren't you Musashi?
무사시 아니냐!
Baiken!
바이켄!
Long time no see-dasu!
오랜만이오!
Glad to see you! And that would mean...
이야, 반갑네! 그 말은?
Everyone, take your swords in!
모두 칼을 거두어라!
-Mr. Baiken! -Baiken!
-바이켄 님! -바이켄!
I'm not going to make excuses. I was very rude to you. Please forgive me, princess!
모른다고 하지는 않겠습니다. 큰 무례를 저질렀습니다. 용서해 주십시오, 센히메 님!
Osenchan, that is! Osenchan!
오센짱이야! 오센짱!
Oh, Osenchan, is it?
아, 오센짱입니까...
More importantly, why is Baiken here?
그보다도, 바이켄은 왜 여기에?
I finally got a job under Date clan!
이 센다이 다테 가 아래 결국 취직했다!
Really-dasu?!
정말이오?!
Congratulations. That's good to know.
축하해. 잘 됐네.
Congratulations from me.
그건 축하드립니다.
Thank you!
고맙수!
But why did you attack us?
근데 왜 우리에게 덤벼들었소?
I was assigned a mission to stop bad people from destroying Date clan.
다테 가를 쳐부수려고 하는 악인이 오니까. 그걸 막으라는 임무를 얻었다.
-From who-dasu? -Date Akinokami, the uncle of the feudal lord, Kamechio.
-누구에게이오? -다테 아키노카미라는 성주 다테 카메치오의 숙부다.
Date Akinokami?
다테 아키노카미?
But I was wrong! Just come to my home for now! I welcome all of you!
그래도 틀렸네! 자, 어쨌든 우리 집으로 와라! 환영한다!
W- welcome? Will you give us food-dasu?!
화, 환영이라면 밥도 나오오?
Of course!
물론이지!
Yay! Food! F o o d! Food!
야호! 밥이다! 밥 이 다! 밥이다!
Stop it! How unsightly of you!
적당히 해라! 꼴불견이다!
I told you that you are being unsightly!
꼴불견이랬지!
Tch, they knew each other?
칫, 아는 사이였군.
Oh, maybe I might be able to use Musashi and Kojirō's technique for my own good.
잠깐, 무사시, 코지로 실력을 이 기회에 이용할 수도 있겠구나.
I- is this Baiken's house-dasu?
이, 이게 바이켄의 집이오?
What a big house-dasu!
거대한 집이오!
Well, it's not really that big!
아니, 그럴 정도까진 아니다!
Welcome back.
어서 오세요.
Awesome-dasu...
대단하오...
I'm back!
지금 돌아왔다!
Brother, welcome back!
형님! 어서오세요.
-Welcome!
-오세요!
Hey, Ikken, Niken, and Oharu! You look well-dasu!
어, 잇켄, 니켄, 오하루! 건강해 보이오!
-It's Musashi! -Musashi!
-어! 무사시다! -무사시다!
This must be Mr. Musashi! It's been a long time!
이건이건 무사시 님! 오랜만입니다.
Huh, what's up-dasu, Ikken?
어라, 무슨 일이오, 잇켄...
Ikken asks us to be formal, since our brother Baiken became a proper warrior!
잇켄 형은 바이켄 형이 충실한 무사가 되었으니까 모두 격식을 높이 차리래.
How praiseworthy of Ikken-dasu!
이야, 잇켄 대단하오!
Splendid, splendid, splendid-dasu!
호화, 호화! 호화롭소!
Eat as much as you want!
사양말고 막 먹으쇼!
You don't have to tell me that-dasu!
말 안 해도 먹소!
Nikken! Act like a warrior, since you live in a warrior's house!
닛켄! 무사의 집에 사는 자는 무사답게!
Well said!
좋은 말 하는구나!
That's very different from Mr. Someone.
누군가 씨하고는 크게 다르네.
Huh? Did you say something?
응? 뭐라 했소?
Anyway, Baiken, you've succeeded in your life-dasu!
그래도, 바이켄도 출세했소!
It's all thanks to Date Akinokami, for letting me live here!
내가 여기 살게 해 준 다테 아키노카미 덕이다!
He must have seen through Mr. Baiken's abilities.
바이켄 님의 실력이 보였던 것일까요.
Of course he did-dasu.
물론이오.
The truth is, Nue, a monster, is giving pain to Date Kamechio, the feudal lord.
실은 성주 다테 카메치오에게 요괴 누에가 달려들어서 말이야.
Nue?
누에?
Nue is a monster from a long time ago that jumps up onto a shrine in midnight and clings to royal palace of the time.
누에라는 것은 먼 옛날에 한밤중에 신전 위에 펄쩍 뛰어 올라 당시의 궁궐에 매달리는 괴물로,
When Minamoto's Yorimasa took it down with his arrow,
미나모토의 요리마사가 쏘아 잡아 보니
he found that Nue had a head of a monkey, a body of a raccoon, a tail of a snake, and hands and feet of a tiger.
그 누에는 머리는 원숭이, 몸통은 너구리, 꼬리는 뱀, 손발은 호랑이였다고 하는 존재이다.
-I brought all the people. -Come in.
-손님을 데려왔습니다. -들어와라.
Welcome. I am Date Akinokami.
잘 오셨구려. 내가 다테 아키노카미다.
-I'm... -Mr. Musashi, Mr. Kojirō, and Ms. Sen.
-나는... -무사시 님, 코지로 님에 센 님.
I heard from Baiken. Both of you are top-class martial artists.
바이켄에게서 들었습니다. 두 분 다 일류 무예가라고.
I sincerely apologize for making them attack you based on a false information.
그런데도 어젯밤은 틀린 정보를 믿고 습격하고 해서 실례했습니다.
It's alright since you know that it was a misunderstanding-dasu.
오해를 풀었으면 그걸로 좋소.
And now you're saying that you'll help us get rid of Nue...
게다가 또 이번에는 누에 퇴치를 도와주신다니.
Right!
그렇소!
It seems that they have prior experiences of eliminating monsters.
지금까지 요괴를 퇴치한 일이 있는 것 같구려.
That's reassuring.
그건 든든하네.
She's suffering from Nue...
누에에게 시달리고 있는 녀석...
Kamechi was called as a wise ruler for a young person, but now she has been bedridden for a while.
젊지만 명군이라고 불렸던 성주, 카메치오는 쭉 몸져 누워 앓는 소리만 할 뿐.
Does that Nue come out every night?
누에는 매일 밤 나오나요?
No, I wouldn't say every night,
아니, 매일 밤이라고 할 것까지는 없지만,
but still it seems that it's gonna appear today's night.
오늘 밤에 나타날 것 같은 기미가...
This really is bad. Who is governing then, when the lord is like this?
이건 너무하네요. 성주가 이 상태여서야는 누가 정치를 하고 계시나요?
Harada Kainosuke, the chief retainer.
신하 총괄인 하라다 카이노스케 님이다.
Harada Kainosuke...
하라다 카이노스케...
Everyone! Thank you for your efforts.
모두들! 수고했다.
He's Harada Kainosuke, the chief retainer.
신하 총괄인 하라다 카이노스케 님이다.
I'll tell you about him. Mr. Harada is the commander in chief of exterminating Nue.
이 사람들에 대해서 말해 주자면, 하라다 님은 누에 퇴치의 총지휘관이다.
I wonder who is Mr. Kojirō.
코지로 님은 어느 분이신가.
Yessir, that is me.
예, 저입니다.
Oh, I heard about the excellence of Tsubamegaeshi of yours!
오, 그 쪽의 츠바메가에시의 대단함은 들어서 안다!
That definitely is reassuring and makes me happy! I'll be relying on you!
든든하니 크게 기쁘군! 의지하겠어!
Thank you.
예.
Uh, how about my Niten'ichiryū, the world-famous technique?
어, 저, 제 이천일류도 유명하고...
Niten'ichiryū? Never heard of it.
이천일류? 몰라.
Then everyone, please do your best!
그럼 모두들, 나머지는 잘 부탁한다!
It's a discourtesy to not know about Niten'ichiryū-dasu!
이천일류를 모르다니 실례이오!
This is bad!
큰일이다!
It's going to fly to here!
날아올 거야!
What's up now?
무슨 일이야?
It seems that a monster is approaching-dasu.
요괴가 다가오는 기운이 드오.
From the roof side.
그것도 천장 방향에서이오.
Did you get it?
숨통이 끊겼나?!
Do not inhale the smoke!
연기를 마시지 마라!
Everyone are now in trouble. What kind of monster is Nue? Wait for the stormy latter half!
위기에 처한 모두들. 과연 누에는 어떤 요괴인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
So that must be Nue-dasu...
저게 누에이오....
It is trying to brainwash Kamechi.
카메치오를 세뇌하려 하고 있어.
It ran away-dasu!
도망쳐버렸소!
Right!
좋아!
There-dasu!
저기이오!
Will it be okay?
괜찮아?
Leave it to me-dasu!
맡겨만 두시오!
Musashi!
무사시!
It's gonna run away!
아, 도망치겠어!
Damn it!
젠장!
Damn, I was so close!
젠장, 눈앞에서 놓친 것이오!
Nue's blood-dasu!
누에의 피이오!
That's disgusting!
기분 나빠!
It was sticking to railing-dasu...
난간에 붙어 있었소.
I see! We might be able to find out where did that Nue disappear to.
그렇군! 잘 하면 누에가 어디로 갔는지 찾아낼 수 있을지도 모르겠어.
Good idea, Kojirō, for following Nue's blood traces!
역시 코지로! 누에 피를 쫒아가다니!
Anyway, Baiken's Kusarigama surely did much damage to it since it's all over the road-dasu!
그래도 계속 이어져 있다니, 바이켄의 쿠사리가마가 꽤나 깊은 상처를 남겼나 보오.
I hope we can find this out properly...
잘 밝혀낼 수 있으면 좋겠다만...
It must've went inside that door-dasu...
분명 저 문 안으로 들어간 것 같소.
But why would something that came from the sky go through a door?
그래도 하늘에서 내려온 것이 굳이 문 안으로 들어가다니...
Anyway let's go find it out-dasu!
어쨌든 한번 가 보오!
Harada?
하라다?
Harada? That chief retainer?
하라다라니, 그 신하 총괄?
Is this Harada Kainosuke's house-dasu?
하라다 카이노스케의 집이오?
What is going on here?
이게 대체 무슨 일이냐.
Kojirō harbored a big suspicion. What could be his suspicion?
코지로는 거대한 의혹을 품었다. 그러나, 과연 그 의혹은 무엇인가?
What? You're here to make me make me disembowel?!
뭐라? 반역자로 할복시키러 왔다고?
You are charged for toying with the feudal lord and making her go crazy using a monster named Nue!
요괴 누에를 써서 영주를 농해 미치게 하고, 원하는 대로 부린 죄.
You are a criminal who might even tried to murder the lord and take control of the whole Date clan!
가만 두었으면 영주를 살해하고 다테 가를 점령하러 한 대악인 놈!
That is you, Date Akinokami!
그건 다테 아키노카미, 네 쪽인줄 알아라!
You fool! I have a definite evidence.
멍청한 놈. 증거가 분명히 있다.
Evidence, eh? Where?
증거? 어디에?
Nue is hiding inside this house somewhere. That is the definitive evidence!
이 집의 어딘가에 누에가 숨어 있다. 그것이 제일의 증거다!
-There is no Nue here. -Then let me search.
-누에 따위 없다. -그럼 조사해 보겠어.
Agreed! But if you fail to find one, I'll have you disemboweled instead!
좋다! 대신, 찾지 못할 때는, 그 쪽이 할복을 해야 할 테이다!
Sure.
좋다.
Charge!
이랴!
There-dasu!
저곳이오!
H- how could it be?!
저, 저게 무슨!
Harada Kainosuke, are you still going to assume innocence?
하라다 카이노스케, 이래도 아직도 시치미뗄 생각인가?
T- this is someone's conspiracy! I know nothing about this!
이, 이건 누군가의 음모다. 난 몰라!
You outrageous bastard!
이 정의롭지 못한 놈!
Nothing matters now! Cut Harada Kainosuke!
이제 상관없다! 하라다 카이노스케를 베어버려라!
Kojirō!
코지로!
Did you lose your mind, Kojirō?!
눈이 뒤집혔나, 코지로.
The real criminal is Date Akinokami, you!
진짜 대악인은 다테 아키노카미, 네놈이다!
W- what-dasu?!
뭐, 뭣이오?
Kojirō! Forget about whatever's in your mind, or I'm not letting this pass!
코지로! 쓸데없는 소리 집어치우지 않으면 그냥은 안 넘어간다!
Is this straw sandal yours, Akinokami?
이 짚신은 아키노카미, 당신 것이지요.
Right, but?
그, 그렇긴 한데.
How are you going to explain this green stain?
이 녹색 얼룩을 뭐라 할 셈인가?
T- that must be Nue's blood.
그, 그건 누에의 피.
Why would it be on Akinokami's sandal?!
왜 아키노카미의 짚신에?!
This is not a blood, but is a green dye.
이것은 피가 아니라 녹색 물감이다.
What's going on here-dasu?
어떻게 된 일이오?
Akinokami acted as if he collapsed in that night, but actually, he ran in front of us with green dye.
아키노카미는 그 밤에 자신도 쓰러진 체를 하면서도 우리보다도 앞질러서 녹색 물감을 들고 갔다.
And he put Nue into the roof of this room. All is to blame Harada for all of his crimes!
그리고 누에를 이 곳의 천장 속에 몰래 넣었다. 그것도 이것도 전부 죄를 하라다 님께 뒤집어씌우기 위해!
How nasty of you!
이 무슨 비열한!
Hey, Kojirō's with a good brain...
어라, 코지로 머리 좋소...
It can't be helped, since you found out!
들킨 이상 어쩔 수 없군!
Nue! Do it! Kill everyone!
누에여! 해라! 말살해 버려라!
Stop!
멈추시오!
Who are you?
너는...
It's been a while, Musashi.
오랜만이군, 무사시.
What? I don't know you-dasu!
뭣이오? 난 당신 따위 모르오!
You're Onihime!
넌 오니히메!
I see. Everything was your trickery.
그렇군. 전부 네 계략이었구나.
Did you realize it now? Musashi and Kojirō, I will take your lives with me using this chance!
이제야 깨달았나, 무사시, 코지로! 너희들 생명도 이 김에 가져가겠다!
Akinokami! Prepare yourself!
아키노카미! 각오하쇼!
This leaves me no choice!
에잇, 이렇게 된 바에는...
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
이천일류 섬광검!
Musashi, you bastard! Remember this!
무사시 놈, 기억해 둬라!
Ain't I cool-dasu?
나, 멋지오!
Thank you for rescuing our Date clan from a crisis.
우리 다테 가의 위기를 구해 주셔서, 참말로 감사했습니다.
No, but instead, we are sorry for suspecting Mr. Harada-dasu!
아니, 우리야말로 하라다 씨를 의심해서 미안하오!
When General Ieyasu hears about this, he'll treat this as an internal
이 소동이 제너럴 이에야스 귀에 들어가면 상속 문제로 내분이 일어난 것으로 취급되어 재산을 몰수당할 게야.
You don't have to worry about that.
그 걱정은 할 필요 없습니다.
I'll tell my grandfather about the truth.
제 할아버지께 진실을 전달해 드리겠습니다.
Grandfather?
할아버지?
Who do you think I am? I am Senhime, the granddaughter of Ieyasu!
여기 있는 날 누구로 아는가! 이에야스의 손녀, 센히메다!
N- no way!
그, 그런!
Mr. Harada Kainosuke, Date clan will be safe. You can relieve.
하라다 카이노스케 님, 다테 가는 무사합니다. 안심하세요.
Yessir! I am very thankful for this!
예! 황송해 몸둘 바를 모르겠습니다!
Are you really going to leave, when Mr. Harada is offering you to stay-dasu?
하라다 씨가 머물게 해 주겠다고 했는데도 정말 여행길을 떠날 것이오?
I realized that I lack discipline, by what happened today.
이번 일로 아직 수행이 부족하다는 걸 깨달았다.
Neither brother nor us doesn't go with working in a castle!
역시 형이나 우리에겐 성에서 근무하는 건 안 맞아!
You're all going to have a difficult time!
모두더욱 고생하게 될 거야!
Well, aren't we all used to it?
뭐, 익숙하잖아?
The felt good, but they did not know what it was about. They continued to travel...
뭔가 기분 좋아지는 것을 가슴에 품으며 무사시 일행은 여행을 계속한다.
However, their next frightening evil hand was right in front of them.
그러나 다음의 무서운 마의 손은 곧장 앞에 다가오고 있었다.
But don't be dispirited, Musashi!
그러나, 기세가 꺾이면 안 된다, 무사시. 내일(明日)이라는 글자는 밝은(明るい) 날(日)이라고 쓴다.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
We went to rescue Santa(三太)'s father and the villagers who found out about the secret gold mountain,
비밀의 금 광산에 대해 알게 된 산타(三太)의 아버지와 마을 사람들을 구출하러 간 우리는 거대한 흙인형 전사하고 만났소.
I thought this was just a huge figure, but even if I cut, it just keeps regenerating-dasu!
이 녀석, 거대할 뿐이라 생각했더니, 베어도 베어도 원래대로!
I can't defeat this with my dual blade skills!
내 이도류로도 이길 수가 없소.
What the?! That Shutentiger from before is controlling that clay warrior!
이 무슨, 흙인형을 조종하고 있던 자는 전의 슈텐타이가.
Next story! Shuten Explodes!
다음 이야기! 슈텐, 대폭발이오
It's a stormy Senpūken-dasu!
질풍노도의 선공권이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Shuten Explodes
슈텐, 대폭발이오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!